UDDIP RANJAN DAS

New Delhi, India ·+91 9311237276

Email · LinkedIn · Twitter · Website

Information Security Specialist with passion for aligning security architecture plans and processes with security standards and business goals. A Red team enthusiast who's interested in Malware research & development along with vulnerability research and network security. Also, a hardware enthusiast, pianist.

EXPERIENCE

AUGUST 2021 – PRESENT
SECURITY RESEARCHER, MINISTRY OF DEFENCE OF INDIA

DECEMBER 2019 – JULY 2020 INFORMATION SECURITY ANALYST, INNEFU LABS PVT. LTD.

- Provided safety reports and data analysis to building managers to inform security processes
- Completed vulnerability scans to identify at-risk systems and remediate issues
- Performed risk analyses to identify appropriate security countermeasures
- Developed plans to safeguard computer files against modification, destruction or disclosure

JULY 2018 – JULY 2019 INFORMATION SECURITY TRAINEE, INNOBUZZ KNOWLEDGE SOLUTIONS

- Taught Students about Penetration testing and Web Application Security
- Perform regular audits to ensure security practices are compliant

EDUCATION

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER APPLICATIONS (PRESENT)

INDIRA GANDHI NATIONAL OPEN UNIVERSITY, NEW DELH

SENIOR SECONDRY - CBSE BOARD - 76% (2016-2017)

INDIRAPURAM PUBLIC SCHOOL, GHAZIABAD

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Red Team Professional (Pentester Academy)
- Advanced Diploma in Information Security (Innobuzz Knowledge Solutions)

SKILLS / INTERESTS

- MALWARE ANALYSIS
- REVERSE ENGINEERING
- PENETRATION TESTING
- ACTIVE DIRECTORY PENTESTING
- RED TEAMING
- SOCIAL ENGINEERING

ACTIVITIES

Currently a member of **PolyX** as a **community malware researcher**.

- Identify and use tools and techniques to conduct static and dynamic analysis of malware, including building a lab environment
- Working knowledge of file formats such as PE, PDF, etc.
- Working knowledge of IDA Pro/Debuggers
- Working knowledge of dynamic/static malware analysis
- Basic knowledge of Windows Operating System Internals (Kernel; Registry; File system; Windows APIs)
- Able to read, analyze disassembly of x86 and x64 binaries

Participated in Operation Chimera organized by Security Blue Team.

TRAININGS

- 101 Reverse Engineering Public Version by U.S. Department of Homeland Security
- Primer on Fuzzing and Exploit Development by National Information Security Council
- Certificate Course in Cybersecurity by Amity Future Academy.
- Wild West Hack Fest's SOC core skills Training.
- ICSI | CNSS Certified Network Security Specialist by International Cybersecurity Institute.
- Autopsy Digital Forensics hands-on training by Basis Technology.
- Fortinet's certified **Network Security Expert**.
- Zero to One in Web Recon by National Information Security Council